Register of the Stanley Kuhl Hornbeck papers, 1900-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject and Correspondence File, 1842-1966 (Boxes 1-452)
  - International Law
    - Hackworth
    - Hong Kong, 1955-1956
    - Immunity of private property
    - In absentia assignment
    - India
    - Nation, most favorite, Hepp (Box 222)
    - Need of a popular understanding of, Root
    - Neutrals, Cooperation of, Tradition, Law and Policy
    - Neutral rights at sea, documents, Shepherd
    - Peace
    - Precedent and codification
    - Publications
    - Recognition
    - Relations
    - Relations, severance of diplomtic
    - Security in Pacific, disarmament and
    - Text, proposed table of contents
    - Treaties, force and interpretation
    - Von Igel case
    - World organization
    - International Missionary Council (Box 223)
  - International News Service
  - International Nickel
  - International Organization, Dumbarton Oaks Conference
    - 1943 September - 1944 August, 1943-1944
    - 1944 September - October (Box 224)
    - Documents and photo from Stettinius
    - General
    - Drafts, Organization of the United Nations' Assembly
  - International PhDs (Box 225)
  - International Platform Association
  - International police force
  - International relations
  - International relations, economic basis
  - International Research on Communist Techniques, Inc.
  - International Telephone and Telegraph Corporation
  - International Travel Register
  - Internationalism
  - Internationalism, bibliography
  - Internees repatriation
  - Internment
  - Inter-Parliamentary Union
  - Intervention
  - Inventories
  - Investment program
  - Iran
  - Ireland
  - Irish Free State Legation
  - ISMS
  - Isolationism
  - Israel
  - "It Can't Be Done"
  - Italy
  - Italian Embassy
  - Jablon, Howard (Box 226)
  - Jacobs, Joseph E.
  - Jacobs, Leonbel, 2.0 folders)
  - Jacobs, Leonbel, exhibition articles
  - Jacobs, Leonbel, S. K. Hornbeck portrait
  - Jacobs, Leonbel, sketches
  - Jacobsen, Paul S.
  - Jacobsen, Herbert
  - Jacquinot, Father
  - Jaffe, Philip J.
    See also: Amerasia
  - Jahncke, Ernest Lee
  - James, Alfred P.
  - James, Andrew
  - James, Eldon R.
  - Jameson, J. F.
  - Jamison, Robert H.
  - Jandrey, Fred W.
  - Janeway, Eliot
  - Jansma, K.
  - Japan
    - General
    - 1918 - 1946, 5.0 folders) (Box 227)
    - Miscellaneous, 4.0 folders)
    - Abbott (Box 228)
    - Activities in Europe before and After Pearl Harbor, Ghambashidze, 1946
    - Activities in other countries
    - American commerce
    - American commerce, Japanese treatment of, 1914
    - American Embassy
    - American-Japan Society Directory
    - American-Japanese relations, National Committee of American Japanese Relations
    - American-Japanese roots of misunderstanding
    - Anglo-Japanese alliance
    - Anti-American sentiment, 1924
    - Armed forces, 1931-1943
    - Art
    - Assistance to
    - Atrocities, 2.0 folders)
    - Australia
    - Baldwin lecture (Box 229)
    - Banking
    - Barrows, Thirteen Points
    - Baseball in 1934
    - Bernhardt
    - Bibliography
    - Biographies
    - Black Dragon Society
    - Book reviews
    - Brock, H. J., "When Japan First Looked to the West"
    - Budget
    - Budget, 1919, 1922-1923
    - Buell, R. L., "Development of Anti-Japanese Agitation in the United States"
    - Burton, Japan as World Power
      See also: "Japan, World Power: Burton on"
    - Bushido
    - Business
    - Caldwell, Lieutenant W. W.
    - California
    - "California and the Japanese," by Payson J. Treat
    - California, Japanese in, by James D. Phelan
    - California difficulty
    - California, Japanese question in
    - "California and Pacific Questions," Pacific Review, 1920
    - California politics
    - California, school question
    - Capacity, circa 1940
    - Cartoons
    - Case for (Makino)
    - Characteristics
    - Chemical trade
    - China and Japan (Index: China file list of titles in China file) (Box 230)
    - China-Japan War, effect on China and the "Scramble,", 1895
    - China, 1909-1914
    - China Policy, anonymous, 1911-1918
    - China, policy toward, 1911-1918
    - China-Japan Agreements of 1915
    - China, economic activity in, 1915-1920
    - China, Japanese demands on, 1916
    - China, Japan's hand in, 1916-1917
    - China relations, 1917
    - Memo in reply to Chinese official claim, circa 1920
    - China trade, 1921
    - China policy, Anderson on, 1922
    - China, economic, 1923
    - Japan's China policy, Tanaka, 1927
    - Note, Japan to China, 1931 October 9
    - China, special position in, 1939
    - China, relations with, 1942-1943
    - China (Nationalist) Treaty, 1952 April 28
    - Clippings, 1900-1920 (Box 231)
    - Press clippings (Reinsch?), 2.0 folders)
    - Press clippings, 2.0 folders) (Box 232)
    - Clippings, 1922-1924 (Box 233)
    - Clippings, 1924 (Box 234)
    - Press clippings
    - Clippings, circa 1960; 2.0 folders)
    - Coal (Box 235)
    - Commerce and Industry, Horne, 1914-1919
    - Commodities, Situation Respecting Fundamental, A. N. Young, 1918
    - Communist efforts, 1957-1958
    - Contemporary politics, bibliography, 1927
    - Copper, production and trade
    - Copyright law
    - Coronation, 1928
    - Currency
    - Debt
    - Debuchi
    - Declaration of war
    - Defeats of
    - Demands, the Japanese, 1916
      See also: Manchuria: Japanese Demands
    - Destiny
    - The Diet, Clement on
    - Diplomatic, 1917
    - Documents from McNelly, 1962
    - Domestic, 1918
    - Duality
    - Earthquake
    - Economic, 1914-1922 (Box 236)
    - Economic, general, 2.0 folders)
    - Economic development, 1914-1920
    - Economic (O. A. Weller?)
    - Education
    - Emperor of, 1935-1944 (Box 237)
    - Emperor
    - England
    - Entry into World War I
    - Estimate
    - Europe and Japan
    - Exclusion, Japanese, Tsurumi, 1932
    - Expansion
    - Expansion, Problem of, 1920
    - Expansion, Rea, George B., "Where Will Japanese Expand?"
    - Factories (Box 238)
    - Factory law
    - Far East
    - Fascism
    - Feudal organization
    - Finance, general
    - Finance, 1907-1928
    - Finance and trade
    - Finances
    - Financial
    - Financial, Commercial, Industrial, Horne, 1914-1919
    - Financial tables, 1918
    - Foreign policy, 1915-1917
    - Foreign policy, Speech of Minister of Foreign Affairs, 1918 January 22
    - Foreign policy, J. T., 1921
    - Foreign policy, China, Fukien question
    - Foreign policy, China, Count Okuma on
    - Foreign Policy Report
    - Foreign Relations
    - Foreigners, Status of, ownership of land by
    - France, relations with
    - Fujisawa, Dr. R.
    - General, 2.0 folders) (Box 239)
    - Genro, 1924
    - Gentleman's agreement
    - German alliance (alleged), 1919 June 30
    - German-Japanese secret agreement
    - Germany
    - Germany of Asia
    - Germany, relations with
    - Goto's estimate of policy, 1916
      See also: "Japan: Policy: Goto's Estimate of"
    - Government, 2.0 folders)
    - Government, colonial, bibliography
    - Government, parliamentary
    - Government, village, Asakawa
    - Great Britain, relations with
    - Guentyer, Louis, "Japan in Our Boat"
    - Gulick, "American-Japanese Problem"
    - Hawaii, Japanese in and American-Japanese problem (Box 240)
    - Hayasn's memoirs
    - Hearn, Lafcadio
    - Hershey, modern Japan
    - Hideyoshi
    - Hirota
    - Hirota-Hull
    - History
    - History, chronology
    - History, diplomatic, 1905-1915
    - Hobson, war with U.S.
    - Hornbeck on, Japan's Monroe Doctrine
    - How to coerce, memo
    - Immigration, 3.0 folders)
    - Immigration (exclusion from), Harvey on, 1924 June 1
    - Immigration, history and question, Buell, 1924
    - Immigration, U.S., 1907, 1916
    - Immigration question, U.S., 1924
    - Immigration question, "Grave Consequences," Saburi, 1924
    - Immigration question, U.S.
    - Immigration question, Woods, 1924
    - Immigration, Wynne and Buell
    - Immigration (Box 241)
    - Imperialism
    - "Imperialism and Liberalism in Japan," Ballantine
    - Imperialism, visit to United States
    - Indo-China, "France in Asia," Gibbons, H. A.
    - Indo-China, French proposal for sale
    - Indo-China, tariff
    - Industrial
    - Industrial development
    - Industrial development of, 1868-1918
    - Industrialization
    - Industry
    - International loan
    - Invasions of
    - Ishii, memoirs
    - Jenks, "Japan in Action,", 1919
    - Kaneko
    - Kato, Premier, Admiral
    - Kawakami, K. K., on "Japan and Her Vital Necessities"
    - Kawakami, in China
    - Kobe Strike, 1921
    - Korea, Japan in
    - Krupensky correspondence about Japan treaties, Lansing-Ishii, etc.
    - Labor problem (Box 242)
    - Langer
    - Lansing - Ishii Agreement
    - League of Nations, Appeal to Japan, 1932 February 16
    - League of Nations, relations with
    - Legal system
    - Literature
    - Magdalena Bay
    - Magdelena Bay Episode, Hart, 1912
    - Makino, "The Case for Japan,", 1919
    - Manchuria, the case for Japan in
    - Manchuria, position in
    - Marcosson, Issac F., "The Japanese Smoke Screen"
    - McCormick, "Menace of Japan," review and notes
    - McLaren, "Political History of Japan," review
    - Military government
    - Military plans
    - Miller, Ransford
      See also: Japan: Political
    - Mistakes regarding
    - Mongolia, 1919
    - Monopolies
    - Monroe Doctrine
    - Monroe Doctrine for Asia
    - Morale
    - Nakahama (Box 243)
    - "Naval Power," by Hector C. Bywater
    - Navy
    - Navy, 1931-1941
    - Navy and Army
    - New order in Asia
    - Newspapers
    - No trespass, 1934; 2.0 folders)
    - Note, U.S. to Japan, 1931 November 4; 2.0 folders)
    - Notes
    - Nuisance Activities
    - Official statements (Box 244)
    - Oil
    - Okuma Declaration, 1915
    - Okuma on "Statesmanship"
    - Open courts
    - Opinions concerning
    - Oriental Development Co.
    - Ozaki
    - Panay Incident, memoranda and reports, 2.0 folders)
    - Panay Incident, press clippings, 2.0 folders)
    - Patriotism
    - Peace Commissioners (Box 245)
    - Peace terms
    - Peace, Treaty of 1951, Manichi Inquiries
    - Peace with United States
    - Pearls
    - Perry, Commodore
    - Personalities
    - Personalities, photos
    - Personnel
    - Petroleum in
    - Plans for
    - "Pledges"
    - Policy, 1918, circa 1930
      See also: Japan: Foreign Policy
    - Policy, 1932-1944 (Box 246)
    - Policy, evidences about, M. Notes
    - Policy, Goto's estimate of, 1916
    - Political to 1917
    - Political, Domestic, circa 1918
    - Political, liberal or conservative, 1919
    - Political, 1924, 1928, 1930-1931; 4.0 folders)
    - Political and industrial
    - Political and industrial, 1916-1917; 4.0 folders) (Box 247)
    - Political parties
    - Political, party government
    - Political psychology, Reinsch, 1905
    - Politics and politicians, manuscript (3 boxes) (Box 248)
    - Population and industrial development
    - Population question
    - Portsmouth Treaty
    - Post office
    - Postwar
    - Press
    - Prince and Heir Apparent
    - Promises, 1931-1941 (Box 249)
    - Propaganda
    - Protest, Shanghai situation, 1932 February 15
    - Race question
    - Racial characteristics (anthropology)
    - Railroads
    - Religion
    - Religions, modern
    - Resources, 1942-1944
    - Restrictions on trade of
    - "Rice" riots
    - Roosevelt - Taft diplomacy, 1910
    - Running amuck, 1941
    - Russia and
    - Russia, Japan attacks
    - Russia, relations with Soviet
    - Russia, Treaty of Neutrality, 1941 April 13
      See also: Soviet Union: Soviet - Japanese Treaty of Neutrality
    - Russo-Japanese Agreement of 1916
    - Russo-Japanese Agreement, special information, 1916
    - Russo-Japanese War, diplomatic antecedents and U.S. Agency
    - Russo-Japanese War, China, U.S., 1904
    - Russo-Japanese War
    - Saito (Japanese ambassador) (Box 250)
    - Saito (Japanese charge d' affaires)
    - Saito, Ambassador Saito's proposal, 1934
    - Saito, general
    - Sakantani (Box 251)
    - School question in U.S.
    - Sculpture
    - Secret agreements, Great Britain, France, Russia
    - Shibata, "What Japan is Thinking"
    - Shibusawa
    - Shidehara on policy, 1927
    - Shimonoseki
    - Shimonoseki, indemnity, Return of, 1917
    - Shimonoseki, Treaty of
    - Shipping
    - Shippings Board, negotiations
    - Shotwell, "Japan's Hope for Peace"
    - Social
    - Social unrest
    - Social unrest, Abbott
    - Society
    - Sociology
    - Soldiers
    - Special Commissioner Van Kol
    - Statesmen
    - Statesmen, Sketches, by Fujisawa
    - Statistics
    - Subsidies
    - Syllabus of six lectures and materials
    - Tanaka Memorial, 1929
    - Tariff
    - Tariff, 1921
    - Tariff, bibliography
    - "Tariff of Japan, Customs," Tariff Series no. 28 and Supplements
    - Tariff and trade: bibliography
    - Tax, income
    - Taxation
    - Terrorist agencies
    - Theatre
    - Tobacco monopoly
    - Tokyo coups d'etat
    - Tokyo situation
    - Tourist information, 1929
    - Trade, 2.0 folders) (Box 252)
    - Trade during the war, export
    - Trade tables, 1918
    - Trade with America, 1919
    - Trade with Canada, 1918
    - Trade and tariff, writings, 1914, 1917
    - Transportation
    - Treat, P. J., "Japan's Leadership in Asia"
    - Treaties (Box 253)
    - Treaties, commercial, list
    - Treaty, Bolivia
    - Treaty, China Agreements, China's protest, 1915
    - Treaty, France, Convention, 1907
    - Treaty, Netherlands, 1912
    - Treaty, Paraguay, 1919
    - Treaty, Russia, 1907
    - Treaty, Russia, Treaty Alliance, 1916
    - Treaty, Russia, Secret, 1907, 1910, 1912
    - Treaty, Russia, Secret, Dennis
    - Treaty, Russia, 1916
    - Treaty, U.S., 1911
    - Treaty negotiations
    - Tsushima Straits, Battle of
    - Twenty-one Demands on on China
      See also: China, Twenty-one Demands
    - U.S., 1908, 1919, 1932
    - U.S., "Cooperation"
    - U.S., economics
    - U.S., the Japanese loan scheme, Shibusawa, Rea, 1916
    - U.S., Panama tolls, Japanese relation to repeal, 1913-1914
    - U.S., political
    - U.S., Reinsch on
    - U.S., representatives to, diplomatic
    - U.S., war problem
    - U.S., White, Hugh on, 1921
    - U.S., general
    - U.S., Kuhn, 1953
    - U.S., conversations (Box 254)
    - U.S., relations
    - U.S., relations, 1941 November 26
    - U.S. war with Japan (Box 255)
    - Wages
    - Wakatsuki and Shidehara speeches, 1927 January
    - War College estimate, 1923
    - War costs and contributions
    - War, declaration when entering, McCormick
    - War forecasts
    - War, Japanese-German negotiations during the war
    - War, "Japan in the War," by P. J. Treat
    - War, part in
    - Wealth of
    - Webster, C. K., "Japan at the Crossroads,", 1928
    - Who's Who
    - Winston, A. P., "Economic Activity of Japan in China"
    - Women
    - World power, Burton on
    - Japanese (Box 256)
    - Abroad
    - Broadcasts
    - Cabinet
    - Debuchi, Mr. (ambassador)
    - Demands at Peking, 1919 February 2
    - Embassy (Box 257)
    - Futura, Count
    - Horinouchi, Mr. Kensuke, Ambassador
    - Imperial Party, U.S., 1931
    - Ishii, Viscount
    - Legation
    - Matsukata, Otohiko (Box 258)
    - Matsuoka, Yosuke
    - Nakamuru (House of Peers)
    - Nitobe, Dr Inazo
    - Nomura, Admiral (ambassador)
    - Obata, Shigeyoshi
    - Ozaki, Youkie
    - People, the
    - Personages
    - Propaganda
    - Soyeshima, Count
    - Studies, Society for
    - Tokugawa, Prince Iesato
    - Uchida, Viscount, 1919
    - Uchida - Wilson
    - Yoshizawa, Mr. K.
  - Jarman, Roger R.
  - Jarvis, Robert Y.
  - Javits, Lt. Col. J. K.
  - Jefferson (Thomas) Centennial Commission (Box 259)
  - Jefferson, Thomas
  - Jehol
  - Jenkins, Douglas
  - Jenkins, Douglas, Jr.
  - Jenkins, Elsa
  - Jenkins, James Douglas
  - Jenkins, L. S.
  - Jenkins, R. D.
  - Jersey City, Rowland, 1950
  - Jessup, Philip C.
  - Jester, Perry N.
  - Jettick, Enna, October, 1959
  - Jhung, C.
  - Johansen, August E.
  - Johns Hopkins Press
  - Johns, Varner
  - Johnson, Arthur A.
  - Johnson, Mrs. F. I.
  - Johnson, Hallett
  - Johnson, Herschel V.
  - Johnson, Hiram
  - Johnson, John D.
  - Johnson, Lewis Jerome
  - Johnson, L. B., President
  - Johnson, Nelson T.
    - General
    - 1929-1930
    - 1931-1934 (Box 260)
    - 1935-1940 (Box 261)
    - 1941-1943, 1950-1966 (Box 262)
    - Comments
    - Obituaries
    - Review of Fairbank's "The U.S. in China"
  - Johnson, R. Curtis (Box 263)
  - Johnson, Ruth L.
  - Johnson, Allen
  - Johnstone, William C.
  - Joint Army-Navy Staff College
  - Joint Intelligence Committee
  - Joint War Aid Committee, U.S. and Canada
  - Jones, Chester Lloyd
  - Jones, Reverend E. Stanley
  - Jones, Jenkin Lloyd
  - Jones, Joseph M.
  - Jones, Lenora H.
  - Jones, Wesley A.
  - Jordan, A. Homer
  - Jordan, Richard H.
  - Josselyn, Paul
  - Journalists, Netherlands
  - Joyce, Kenyon A.
  - Joyce, Robert P.
  - Judaism
  - Judd, Walter
  - Judd, Walter, comment on China "White Paper,", 1949 August
  - Judd, Walter, 1965
  - Judd, Walter, comments on Chinese intellectuals
  - Judd, Walter, Committee Report, 1954 January
  - Jung, Harry A.
  - Kabayama, Count (Box 264)
  - Kagawa, Dr. Toyhiko
  - Kalijarvi, Thorsten
  - Kalorama
  - Kane, Albert E.
  - Kaneko, Kentaro
  - Kaplan, Sheldon Z.
  - Karig, Walter
  - Karpovich, Michael
  - Karsten, Karl
  - Kasai, Juji
  - Kashmir
  - Katz, William
  - Kaufman, David E.
  - Kauffmann, Mrs. Henrik
  - Kavanagh, Edward C.
  - Kawakami, K. K.
  - Kaya, Prince and Princess
  - Kearny, Lawrence
  - Keblinger, Wilbur
  - Keenleyside, H. L.
  - Kefauver, Grayson N.
  - Kelchner, Warren H.
  - Keller, Kent E.
  - Keller, (Mrs.) Frances
  - Kellogg, Frank B.
  - Kellogg, Frank B., "War Prevention Policy of the United States"
  - Kellogg Pact, invocation of, basic materials and drafts
  - Kellogg - Briand Pact (Pact of Paris), 1928 August 27 (Box 265)
  - Kellogg Treaties
  - Kelso, C. A.
  - Kendall, Mr. & Mrs. Robert Rogers
  - Kenedy, Louis
  - Keneipp, traffic case
  - Kennan, George
  - Kennan, George, 1950
  - Kennedy, Senator Edward M.
  - Kennedy, Mrs. Jacqueline
  - Kennedy, President John F.
  - Kennedy, Joseph
  - Kennedy, Robert F.
  - Kent, Charles
  - Kent, Zolita M. (Mrs.)
  - Kern, J.
  - Kerner, Robert J.
  - Kerr, George A. (Box 266)
  - Kerr, George H., Formosa Betrayed
  - Kerr, John
  - Ketcham, George Franklin, Jr.
  - Ketcham, John B.
  - Keynes, J. M.
  - Kids
  - Kieffer, Paul
  - Kiegley, accident
  - Kiekhofer, William H. (Box 267)
  - Kilpatrick, William H.
  - Kim, Yongjeung
  - King, Delcevare
  - King, Admiral E.
  - King-Hall Newsletter
  - King, Julian M.
  - King, Dr. Martin Luther
  - King, William H.
  - King, Wunsz, manuscript, 1963
  - King, Wunsz, 1960-1966
  - Kingman, Harry L.
  - Kinkead, George B. (Canon)
  - Kinney, Henry W.
  - Kiplinger
  - Kirk, Alexander
  - Kittredge, Tracy B.
  - Kizer, Benjamin H.
  - Klausner, Leopold C.
  - van Kleffens, Margaret
  - Kleiman, M.
  - Klein, Julius
  - Klieforth, Alfred W.
  - Klinefelter, Harry F.
  - Klots, Allen T.
  - Knapp, J. B.
  - Knappen, M. M.
  - Knopf, A. A., Inc.
  - Knowland, Senator William F.
  - Knox, J. W. (Box 268)
  - Knox, (William) Franklin
  - Kohlberg, Alfred
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, Institute of Pacific Relations, etc., 1940-1946
  - Kolaitis, Memas
  - Komatsu, Takashi
  - Konoye, Prince Fumimaro
  - Koo, A. C.
  - Koo, Dr. Wellington
  - Koo, Wellington, Jr.
  - Kooiman, P. J.
  - Korea
    - General
    - General (Box 269)
    - General (Box 270)
    - 1917
    - Annexation, Hulbert, McCormick, Ladd on
    - Briefs for, Dolph
    - Claims
    - Congressional incident, 1920 August
    - Congressional Party at Seoul
    - Crozier on
    - Declaration of Independence
    - Dispatches
    - Economic Development
    - Japan in
    - Peace Conference, Paris
    - Railways, new
    - Secret diplomacy of annexation
    - Treaties
    - Truce, collective security
    - Truman, 1950 June 27
    - U.S. policy, 1950
    - "Young Korea"
  - (United) Korean Committee in America
  - Korean National Movement, 1919
  - Korean petitions
  - Kracke, Edward A., Jr. (Box 271)
  - Krentz, Kenneth C.
  - Kriesberg, Martin
  - Krock, Arthur
  - Kroner, Hayes, A. (Major)
  - Krussell, Mrs. Arlie H.
  - Kshirsagar, Shiwaram K.
  - Kuhl, Bertha and Clara
  - Kuhn, Arthur K.
  - Kung, H. H.
  - Kuo, Miss
  - Kuo, P. W.
  - Kurtz, J. Banks
  - Kurusu, Saburo
  - Kwantung Penninsula
  - Labin, Mme. Suzanne, 1963 (Box 272)
  - Labor problem
  - Lacey, John A.
  - LaCombe, Vernon G.
  - Lady, H. W.
  - La Fargue, Thomas E.
  - Lafollette, Robert M., Jr.
  - LaFuse, George L.
  - Lall, Miss Betty Gotz
  - Lamont, Thomas W., 1930-1943; 4.0 folders)
  - Lanbert, Hudson Motors Company
  - Lancaster, Bruce
  - Lancaster, William W.
  - Lanchow, Red China, MacKay on, 1956
  - Land, Emory S.
  - Landon, Alfred M.
  - Landon and Warner
  - Lane, Arthur Bliss
  - Lane, Darrell
  - Lane, George Bliss
  - Lane, Otho, 1953-1958
  - Langdon - Ishii
  - Langdon, William R. (Box 273)
  - Langdon manuscript
  - Langer, William L.
  - Langhorne, Colonel George T.
  - Langhorne, Mary
  - Language
  - Language materials
  - Lansing-Ishii Agreement, 2.0 folders)
  - Lansing, Robert
  - Lansing, W. H.
  - Laos
  - Lardy, Etienne
  - Larkin, Frederick, building operations
  - Larkin, Fred, 1946
  - Larsen, Emmanual S.
  - Larsen, Henry L.
  - Larson, Arthur
  - Lash, (Mrs.) Raymond A.
  - Lasker, Albert D.
  - Lasker, Bruno
  - Lassing, Capt. W. H.
  - Latin America
  - Latin American Relations of U.S., Conference, 1927
  - Latourette, Kenneth Scott
  - Lattimore, David (Box 274)
  - Lattimore, Owen
  - Laughlin, Mrs. Irwin
  - Laughs
  - Laukhuff, Perry
  - Laundry slips
  - Lautenschlager, S.
  - Law
  - Law School credits
  - Lawrence, David
  - Lawrence of Arabia
  - Lawrence, William B.
  - Lay, Frances
  - Lea, Charlotte Augusta
  - Lea, Homer
  - Leach, Charles N.
  - Leaf, Earl H.
  - League of Nations
    - General
    - Advisory Committee (Box 275)
    - Assembly Resolutions
    - Commission of Inquiry
    - Committee on Technical Cooperation with China
    - Council of, Geneva, 1931 October 13-24
    - Council of, Geneva, 1932
    - Council of, Paris, 1931 November 16 - December 10
    - Council Resolutions (Box 276)
    - Covenant of
    - Declaration, 1932 January 29
    - Relations of United States with
    - Round Table Plan
  - Leahy, Joseph P.
  - Leahy, L. R.
  - Leahy, Admiral William D., 2.0 folders)
  - Leaks
  - Leavell, Mrs. R. Hayne
  - Lebedeff, Ivan
  - Lee, Clark (Box 277)
  - Lee, Edwin F.
  - Lee, Frederic E.
  - Lee, Howard E.
  - Lee, Ivy, Commencement Address
  - Lee, Lt. General John C. H.
  - Lee, William Yinson
  - Leebrick, K. C.
  - van der Leeuw, G.
  - Leeuwarden
  - LeFevre, E.
  - Left, The
  - Lehrbas, Lloyd
  - Leiper, Henry S.
  - Leiser, Clara
  - Leith, C. K.
  - Leith, Gladys
  - Leith-Ross, Sir Frederick
  - LeLacheur, Embert A.
  - Leland, Waldo G.
  - Lend-Lease Agreement
  - Lend-Lease, reverse, 1942-1944
  - Lennox, Emma Buchtel
  - Lentz, Lucy
  - Lentz, Serge, a modern Marco Polo
  - Lentz, George, Jr.
  - Leon, Maurice
  - Leon, Rene
  - Leonard, L. Larry
  - Lerner, Eugene M.
  - Letters of introduction
  - Letter samples
  - Leufkens, H.
  - Levy, (Mrs.) Ernest
  - von Lewinski, Roy and Emma
  - Lewis, A., Jr. (Box 278)
  - Lewis, James Hamilton
  - Lewis, Maj. Gen. John T.
  - Lewis, Lawrence
  - Lewis, Robert E.
  - Leysen, A. H. J.
  - Li, K. C.
  - Liang, Yuen-Li
    See also: Stimson, Henry L. file for his article, "The Pact of Paris as Envisioned by Mr. Stimson...."
  - Liberalism
  - Liberated areas, administration of
  - Liberation